A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, RG 2 FA433
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Office of the Messieurs Rockefeller (OMR) Files, 1878-1972; bulk; 2; 21 Cubic Feet
  - Financial Materials, 1912-1961; 5; 9 box(es)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1941 September 16-29 (Box 45, Folder 588)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1941 October (Box 45, Folder 589)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1941 November 1-3 (Box 45, Folder 590)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1941 November 4-30 (Box 45, Folder 591)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1941 December 2 (Box 45, Folder 592)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1941 December 9-31 (Box 45, Folder 593)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 January 8 (Box 45, Folder 594)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 January 10-26 (Box 45, Folder 595)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 February 1-3 (Box 45, Folder 596)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 February 4-27 (Box 45, Folder 597)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 March 2-4 (Box 45, Folder 598)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 March 10-27 (Box 46, Folder 599)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 April (Box 46, Folder 600)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 May (Box 46, Folder 601)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 June (Box 46, Folder 602)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 July (Box 46, Folder 603)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 August (Box 46, Folder 604)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 September (Box 46, Folder 605)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 October (Box 46, Folder 606)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 November (Box 46, Folder 607)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1942 December (Box 46, Folder 608)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 January 1-15 (Box 46, Folder 609)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 January 16-27 (Box 46, Folder 610)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 February (Box 46, Folder 611)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 March (Box 46, Folder 612)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 April (Box 46, Folder 613)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 May (Box 46, Folder 614)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 June (Box 46, Folder 615)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 July (Box 47, Folder 616)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 August (Box 47, Folder 617)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 September (Box 47, Folder 618)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 October (Box 47, Folder 619)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 November (Box 47, Folder 620)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1943 December (Box 47, Folder 621)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 January (Box 47, Folder 622)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 February (Box 47, Folder 623)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 March (Box 47, Folder 624)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 April (Box 47, Folder 625)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 May (Box 47, Folder 626)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 June (Box 47, Folder 627)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 July (Box 47, Folder 628)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 August (Box 47, Folder 629)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 September (Box 47, Folder 630)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 October (Box 47, Folder 631)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 November (Box 47, Folder 632)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1944 December (Box 47, Folder 633)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Bills Paid, 1940-1944 (Box 47, Folder 633 A)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Household Account - Statements, 1940-1941 (Box 47, Folder 634)
      September - October 1941 statements missing; statements for 1942 - in monthly Bills Paid files.
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Investment Account (Statements), 1934-1936 (Box 48, Folder 635)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Investment Account (Statements), 1937 (Box 48, Folder 636)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Investment Account (Statements), 1938 (Box 48, Folder 637)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Investment Account (Statements), 1939 (Box 48, Folder 638)
    - Personal - Chase Bank - Investment Account (Statements), 1940-1941 (Box 48, Folder 639)
    - Personal - Financial Statements - Annual, 1913-1932 (Box 48, Folder 640)
    - Personal - Financial Statements - Annual, 1934-1938, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 641)
    - Personal - Financial Statements - Portfolio, 1948 (Box 48, Folder 642)
    - Personal - Financial Statements (Oversized file) (Box 53, Folder 713)
    - Personal - Loan Guarantees and Commitments, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 643)
    - Personal - Loans to Individuals, 1939-1942 (Box 48, Folder 644)
    - Personal - Loans to Individuals, 1943-1945 (Box 48, Folder 645)
    - Personal - Loans to Individuals, 1949-1959 (Box 48, Folder 646)
    - Personal - Loans to Individuals (Callahan, Roy), 1952-1959 (Box 48, Folder 647)
    - Personal - Loans to Individuals (Cushing, Alexander - Squaw Valley Development Company), 1949-1960 (Box 48, Folder 648)
    - Personal - Salary Receipts, 1937-1938, 1940 (Box 48, Folder 649)
    - Personal - Securities - General, 1938-1960 (Box 48, Folder 650)
    - Personal - Securities - Holdings and Transactions, 1934-1940 (Box 48, Folder 651)
    - Personal - Taxes and Tax Advice, 1942-1961 (Box 49, Folder 652)
    - Personal - Trusts - Income Payments, 1935, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 653)
    - Personal - Trusts - Statements, 1935-1936 (Box 49, Folder 654)
    - Personal - Trusts - Statements, 1937-1938 (Box 49, Folder 655)
    - Personal - Trusts - Statements, 1939-1940 (Box 49, Folder 656)
    - Personal - Trusts - Statements, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 657)
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller Family, 1878-1972 (bulk 1934-1961); bulk; 6; 3 box(es)
    The LSR Family series is a small group of files concerning LSR's wife, Mary French Rockefeller, and their children. The Mary French Rockefeller materials consist of personal files and of materials relating to the Billings Farm and Mansion and the estate of her mother, Mary Billings French. The personal papers include general correspondence files, contribution records, and financial, school, and gift files. The general files notably contain a few designs and swatches for dresses ordered from the French design house Paquin in the spring of 1940. Other topics include a musical evening that JDR, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller hosted in honor of Mary French Rockefeller and Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller in 1936; the gift of Billings Park to the town of Woodstock in 1953-1956; and her service with the YWCA. Correspondents include JDR, Jr., John French, William Hearst, and Leonard Bernstein. The materials on Mary Billings French, who died in 1951, concern the disposition of her property and estate, and particularly concern the operation, management, and upkeep of the Billings Farm and Billings Mansion in Woodstock, Vermont. There are farm and dairy accounts in both the Mary Billings French files and the Billings Farm and Mansion files. Significant items include a notebook in the Billings Farm and Mansion files that lists the paintings and engravings belonging to Frederick Billings in Woodstock in 1882. The notebook also contains household accounts, 1878-1880, and bible notes. An October 1959 memorandum in the Billings Farm file concerns the mansion's Tiffany windows.
    Files relating to LSR's children are restricted from scholarly access.
    Financial files relating to Mary French Rockefeller are restricted from scholarly access.
    - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman (Case) - General, 1936-1957 (Box 49, Folder 658)
    - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman (Case) - Contributions, 1958-1961 (Box 49, Folder 659)
    - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman (Case) - Debut, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 660)
    - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman (Case) - Finances, 1952-1959 (Box 49, Folder 661)
    - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman (Case) - Gifts, 1936-1959 (Box 49, Folder 662)
    - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman (Case) - Marriage, 1956 (Box 49, Folder 663)
    - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman and Marion French - Camp, 1947-1948 (Box 49, Folder 664)
    - Rockefeller, Laurance, 1967, 1972 (Box 49, Folder 665)
    - Rockefeller, Lucy Aldrich - General, 1941-1961 (Box 49, Folder 666)
    - Rockefeller, Lucy Aldrich - Debut, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 667)
    - Rockefeller, Lucy Aldrich - Gifts, 1941-1960 (Box 49, Folder 668)
    - Rockefeller, Marion French - General, 1938-1961 (Box 49, Folder 669)
    - Rockefeller, Marion French - Contributions, 1959-1961 (Box 49, Folder 670)
    - Rockefeller, Marion French - Debut, 1956 (Box 49, Folder 671)
    - Rockefeller, Marion French - Gifts, 1938-1959 (Box 49, Folder 672)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - General, 1935-1949 (Box 50, Folder 673)
      Includes Paquin dress designs
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - General, 1935-1949 (Box 50, Folder 673 A)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - General, 1950-1961 (Box 50, Folder 674)
      Includes report on Carline Zachry Institute of Human Development, 1950; William Hearst and Hearst Castle; Billlings Park; 1961 speech to Atlanta YWCA
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - General, 1950-1961 (Box 50, Folder 674 A)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Billings Farm and Mansion, 1878-1882 (Box 50, Folder 675)
      Notebook listing paintings and engravings in Frederick Billings' Woodstock mansion, 1882. Household accounts, 1878-1880; bible notes.
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Billings Farm and Mansion, 1947-1955 (Box 50, Folder 676)
      Property exchanges, budgets, maintenance notes, dairy operations.
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Billings Farm and Mansion, 1956-1961 (Box 50, Folder 677)
      Renovations; farm and mansion accounts, 1956-1957; copy of 1954 deed from Elizabeth F. Hitchcock to Mary French Rockefeller. Letter from Thomas Devine concerning mansion architect and Tiffany windows.
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Contributions, 1936-1962 (Box 50, Folder 678)
      Chronological arrangement. Includes contribution reports for 1940, 1947-1950
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Contributions (A-L) (Box 50, Folder 679)
      Alphabetical. Dessoff Choirs, Inc., 1951-1962; First Congregational Church (Woodstock, VT), 1938-1961; Foundation for Christian Living (Pawling, NY), 1959-1961
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Contributions (M-P) (Box 50, Folder 680)
      Alphabetical. Maternity Consultation Service, Inc., 1956-1957; National Federation of Settlements, Inc., 1946-1952; New York Women's Bible Society, 1960-1961; Open House for Officers, 1943-1944; Presbyterian Home for Aged Women (New York, NY), 1948-1961
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Contributions (Q-R) (Box 50, Folder 681)
      Alphabetical. Republican National committee, 1936-1940; Rosemary Hall (Greenwich, CT), 1937-1938, 1947-1961
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Contributions (S) (Box 50, Folder 682)
      Alphabetical. School Art League of New York City, 1937-1961; Southern New York League for Nursing, 1955-1961; Studio 135, Inc. (Zoltan Hecht scholarships) (New York, NY), 1959-1961; Swiftwater Girl Scout Council (Woodstock, VT), 1959, 1961
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Contributions (T-U) (Box 50, Folder 683)
      Alphabetical. Thursday Club (NY), 1949-1950, 1957, 1960; United Church Women, Woodstock Area Council, 1955-1961
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Contributions (V) (Box 50, Folder 684)
      Alphabetical. Vermont Children's Aid Society, Inc., 1942-1961; Vermont State Symphony Orchestra Association, Inc., 1950-1961; Vermont Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1950-1961
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Contributions (W-Z), Still Images: 2 black-and-white glossy prints (5" x 7"), with taped-on captions. (Box 50, Folder 685)
      Alphabetical. Woodstock Historical Society, Inc., 1944-1961; Young Men's Christian Association of the Windsor District, Inc. (Camp Billings) (VT), 1951-1956. Includes two photos of Woodstock Historical Society House, northwest room, downstairs.
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Finances - General, 1934-1939 (Box 50, Folder 686)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Finances - General, 1940-1954 (Box 51, Folder 687)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Finances - Power of Attorney, 1935 (Box 51, Folder 688)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Finances - Securities Holdings, 1936-1938 (Box 51, Folder 689)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate, 1951 June (Box 51, Folder 690)
      Memoranda on property, mansion, and farm operations
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate, 1951 July (Box 51, Folder 691)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate, 1951 July (Box 51, Folder 691 A)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate, 1951 August-November (Box 51, Folder 692)
      Memoranda on property, mansion, and farm operations. Includes affidavit on life of Mary Billings French (September 18, 1951) and estate inventory, (October 10, 1951).
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate, 1951 December (Box 51, Folder 693)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate, 1952 January-May (Box 51, Folder 694)
      Billings Farm management and accounts
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate, 1952 July-August (Box 51, Folder 695)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate, 1953-1954 (Box 51, Folder 696)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Estate (Oversized file), 1951 (Box 53, Folder 714)
      Sketch map of Billings Estate, Woodstock, Vermont (copy), 1951
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - French, Mary Billings - Memorial Fund, 1952-1953 (Box 51, Folder 697)
      Gift of Billings Park to town of Woodstock. NAR donation to cover taxes and maintenance
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Gifts, 1934-1960 (Box 51, Folder 698)
      Wedding, Christmas, and birthday gifts from JDR, Jr.
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Gifts, 1934-1960 (Box 51, Folder 698 A)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Greenwich Property, 1935-1938, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 699, Drawer E11, Drawer 56)
      Subdivision of French property between Lake Avenue and Round Hill Road. Survey Map of Property, December 1935
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - School Records, 1914 (Box 51, Folder 700)
      Report cards from Rosemary Hall, Greenwich, October-December 1914
    - Rockefeller, Mary French (Mrs. LSR) - Trust, 1936-1948, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 701)
  - Audiovisual materials, 7
    Alphabetical.
    Includes home movie footage, video recordings of speeches, as well as some commercial and public films relating to LSR's business and philanthropic interests.
    When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction. All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 2 business days, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted from access at the discretion of RAC.
    - Colter Bay Dedication: American Indian Feast, 1972 June 29; 1/2 inch videotape; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes (Box 1, Reel AV 11555)
      Access copy available.
      Video documentation of event with speech by LSR.
    - Colter Bay Dedication: Interviews, 1972 June 29; 1/2 inch videotape; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes (Box 1, Reel AV 11557)
      Informal interviews with attendees of Colter Bay Dedication Ceremony, including LSR.
    - Competition and Big Business, Sound, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 869)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
      Educational film based on a study by Dr. A.D.H. Kaplan. Produced by Encyclopedia Britannica.
    - Discovering Underwater Photography, Sound, Color, 30 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 864)
      Eastman Kodak Company presents "Discovering Underwater Photography" a commercial advertising film produced by filmed in Caneel Bay. This film is a fictionalized account of a family and their friends vacationing in the Virgin Islands and using underwater photography. They learn about underwater photographic equipment, how to photograph underwater and scuba diving. Copyright 1974, Eastman Kodak Company.
    - Dorado Beach: Pro-Am and Opening, 1958 December 3; Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1098)
      1958 footage showing the town and beaches at Dorado Beach. LSR is seen golfing with wife Mary and guests.
    - Fresh-laid Plans, 1950; Sound, Color, 10 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 868)
      Animated feature about business, subsidies, and the law of supply and demand. Produced by Harding College and John Sutherland Productions.
    - Flying the Boeing 707, circa 1950s; 16mm film (Reel AV 66)
      LSR and others on promotional flight from Seattle WA to Los Angeles CA
    - Jackson Lake Lodge Opening Ceremony, 1955 June 11; 16mm film on 1 inch videotape; Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes (Box 1, Reel AV 11567)
      Opening ceremonies including ceremonial Indian dance, banquet, and guests LSR, Conrad Wirth, Kenneth Chorley, Harold and Josephine Fabian, Gene Setzer, and Secretary of the Interior Fred Seaton.
    - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Memorial Parkway Dedication and Ribbon Cutting Ceremony, 1972 September 18; 1/2 inch videotape; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes (Box 1, Reel AV 11559)
      Dedication and ribbon cutting ceremony with several speeches, including LSR, and informal camera interviews.
    - Laurance Rockefeller interview, circa 1960s; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute; 16mm film (Reel AV 1719)
      Sound bite on NYC street from Laurance Rockefeller about being a VISTA volunteer with urban poor, from NBC.
    - Laurance S. Rockefeller Wedding, 1934 August; Sound, Black and white, 5 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1925)
      Newsreel footage pertaining to the wedding of Laurance Rockefeller to Mary French, in Woodstock, Vermont.
    - Little Dix Bay Dedication II, 1964 January 18; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 71)
      Dedication ceremony with LSR.
    - New York Zoological Society
      All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
      - Living Earth: Birth of the Soil, 1948; Sound, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 59)
        Film from a series produced by Encyclopedia Britannica Films, Inc. for the Conservation Association.
      - Living Earth: This Vital Earth, 16mm film (Reel AV 60)
      - Living Earth: Arteries of Life, 1948; Sound, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 61)
      - Living Earth: Seeds of Destruction, 1948; Sound, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 62)
      - Stars in Stripes, 1949; Sound, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 63)
        Narrative: "Three Little Tigers and How They Grew Up."
    - St. John and the Dedication of the Virgin Islands National Park, 1956; Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1613)
      Ceremonies at historic and natural sites, with LSR in attendance.
    - Queen's Visit to the Virgin Islands, 1965 March 23; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1675)
      Footage from Queen Elizabeth visit to the Virgin Islands, accompanied by LSR, his wife, and other dignitaries. Filmed by G. Hoke.
    - Why Play Leap Frog? Facts and Fun About America, Sound, Color, 10 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 865)
      Animated film about taxes, wages, and costs, produced by Harding College and John Sutherland productions.